(+44) 07568312416

https://www.linkedin.com/in/albertorodriguezpariente/?locale=en_US https://arodpar.github.io/ARP.github.io/ a.rodriguezpar@gmail.com

ALBERTO RODRIGUEZ PARIENTE

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Data analyst with a degree in Business & Management. I have spent the last months learning all I can about Excel, SQL (BigQuery), R (RStudio) and Visualization Tools (Tableau) to move into the data analytics field (Google Data Analytics Certificate – 2023).

I got experience in all different departments of a company (purchasing, customer service, import/export). Worked in many different fields like banking, real state, automation...

Fluent in Spanish and English I have also spent some time learning Mandarin Chinese (HSK4).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

GLOBAL TRADE COORDINATOR AT EU AUTOMATION (STAFFORD, UK)

January 2022 – Present

- Preparing commercial invoices with the proper tariff codes, made in and duties.
- Contact carriers to obtain air/road/sea freight quotes and proceed with the bookings.
- Maintaining up to date data sheets with the documents
 associated to each shipment (C88/SAD/MRN) for import and
 export out of our warehouses based in EU, UK, US and Singapore.
- Ensuring up to date knowledge of legislative requirements.

PURCHASING COORDINATOR AT EU AUTOMATION (STAFFORD, UK)

December 2020 – January 2022

- Check the orders comply with our safety policies.
- Add to the orders different elements like: taxes, costs, discounts...
- Look for better sourcing options.
- Allocate orders to the different members of the purchasing team.
- Advise to the sales team regarding lead times, prices, duties....

PROBLEM RESOLUTION EXECUTIVE AT EU AUTOMATION (STAFFORD, UK)

April 2019 – December 2020

- Contact suppliers to solve technical issues our customers have.
- Send purchase orders to the suppliers for replacements or repairs.
- Check official manuals to identify and solve the simpler issues.

CUSTOMER SERVICE EXECUTIVE AT EU AUTOMATION (STAFFORD, UK)

March 2018 - April 2019

- Approve orders after checking and fixing any mistakes.
 Coordinated at all times with sales and purchasing department to minimize errors and delays.
- Inform the customer during all the process (with emails and over the phone) since we receive the order until the package is delivered and supporting him after it has been delivered.
- Teach new members in the team about the CRM and the different ways to proceed depending on the situation.

BANK TELLER AT BBVA (MADRID, SPAIN)

June 2015 - November 2017

- Process standard teller transactions for customers (+80 transactions per day) and B2B tasks.
- Solve any issues following strict bank and safety policies.
- Promote and up-sell bank products and services (accounts, cards, insurance...) both face to face and over the phone.

FINANCIAL ADVISOR AT KIRON (MADRID, SPAIN)

February 2015 – May 2015

- Exhaustive analysis of the client's credit profile.
- Give advice during the house buying process including the different costs that come with purchasing a new house as notary, taxes, sale of the previous house and inheritances.

COMISS CHEF AT BRIDGE HOUSE HOTEL (CUMBRIA, ENGLAND)

August 2013 – November 2014

FIELD MANAGER AT OLYMPIR (MADRID, SPAIN)

October 2009 - June 2012

LANGUAGES

Spanish – Mother tongue

English – EFSET 74 (C2)

Chinese (Mandarin) - HSK4 (B2) - Currently studying HSK 5

EDUCATION

GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS (COURSERA) 2023

DEGREE IN BUSINESS MANAGEMENT & ADMINISTRATION UNIVERSIDAD REY JUAN CARLOS, MADRID (SPAIN) 2013

Micro and Macroeconomics, Logistics, Accounting, Marketing, Business Ethics, IT.